Bonnie Ward

Anaheim, CA 92806 | 714.392.5346 | bonniesbrightideas@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/baongocward/

PORTFOLIO

bonniesbrightideas.github.io/

DESIGN SKILLS

Agile Methodology
User Research
User Flow
Data Analysis
Competitor Analysis
Flowcharts
Usability Testing
A/B Testing
Wireframe
Information Architecture
User Interface
Rapid Prototyping
Test Result Iterations

TECHNICAL SKILLS

XD / Figma / Sketch / InVision Adobe XD/ Illustrator/ Photoshop/ Lightroom HTML / CSS/ Java Script/ Bootstrap Github

OTHER SKILLS

Communication
Presentation
Storytelling
Desire to learn
Self-aware
Empathy

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate

UC Irvine Irvine, CA | October 2020

BS, Business Administration

UC Riverside Riverside, CA | June 2008

SUMMARY

User-centered UI/UX Designer with a thoughtful approach to problem solving by combining usability viewpoints to design web and mobile applications with an impact. Thrives on creating compelling designs to enhance user experiences to grow brand loyalty, create user delight, and make memorable experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Eli Home | UX-UI Freelance Designer Sep 2020 - present | Anaheim, CA

Collected data from user research to understand what users are doing and why, which included business stakeholders interviews, user interviews and a survey, to analyze and devise a strategy for redesigning a nonprofit organization's website. Defined key problems and ideated solutions empathizing with the user and organization. Created wireframes and tested. Analyzed the test results and iterated. Delivered high fidelity prototype by presentation. Currently in the final review for developing.

Pecan Park Dentistry | Freelance Designer

Sep 2020 | Austin, TX

Rebranded a dentistry website to meet current trends, align with public perception based on user feedback, and remain competitive. Crated a modern and sophisticated brand logo including print and packaging mockups to showcase visual design.

Utah Transit Authority | Property Administrator II

Apr 2015 - Oct 2019 | Salt Lake City, UT

Presented transportation design and planning to stakeholders. Negotiated resources and funding for projects. Managed multiple timelines and deadlines, as well as, adjusted for unforeseen issues/complications. Most valuable experience in the role was learning to adapt to quickly changing environments, be receptive to feedback both positive and negative, work with tight deadlines, and manage large projects by staying calm under pressure while still meeting best practices to offer the best problem-solving solutions.

Corestrategy Corporation | Executive Assistant/ Marketing Associate Jun 2014 – May 2015 | Irvine, CA

Created corporate marketing portfolios with market analysis for clients and events. Most valuable experience in the role was learning to build strong business acumen skills and to not only think analytically but logically to solve complex problems, always keeping an open mind.

PROJECTS

Virtual Education Redesign

https://bonniesbrightideas.github.io/education.html

UX Research, UI Design, & Frontend Development of a school website to improve remote learning.

Role | Project Manager: Team management, time management, excellent communication, collaborate, organization of work, and presenting.

Tools: Google Drive, Gnatt Chart, Trello, Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, Github, Bootstrap 4, HTML 5, CSS 3

Government Website Redesign

https://www.behance.net/gallery/100985587/DHSs-New-Public-Centered-Approach-Case-Study UX Research & UI Design of the U.S. Department of Homeland Security Website to improve public perception by highlighting various agencies and streamlining user flows.

Role | Designer: Heuristics evaluation, Interview moderator, persona creation, defining the problem, empathy mapping, annotations, card sorting, wireframing, prototyping, testing, and iterating.

Tools: XD, Adobe Creative Suite, Zoom, Unsplash

Recycling Mobile App

https://www.behance.net/gallery/100985587/DHSs-New-Public-Centered-Approach-Case-Study UX Research & UI Design, with a team, a social events and networking mobile app focused on ways to build better recycling habits.

Role | Research team member: Collaborate, communicate effectively, Interview, survey, affinity diagram, user journey mapping, empathy mapping, competitive analysis, wireframing, user testing, and iterating.

Tools: XD, Adobe Creative Suite, Zoom, Unsplash, Trello, Miro